stockopedia.co.uk 2018-12-28

# Privacy Policy | Stockopedia

Stockopedia is committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors. This policy sets out how we collect and process your personal data, including any data you may provide through this website, for example when you open an account with us, or when you sign up to receive editorial content.

Stockopedia Limited is the controller and responsible for your personal data ("we", "us" or "our" in this privacy policy). Our registered office is Oxford Centre for Innovation, New Road, Oxford OX1 1BY. We can be contacted on 01865 261 447 or by email at support @ stockopedia.com.

This website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements.

## Personal Information

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you.

  * **Identity Data** , including name, username or similar identifier.
  * **Contact Data** , including billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.
  * **Transaction Data** , including details about payments to and from you. We use Payment Card Industry compliant third-party payment services and we do not store your credit card information.
  * **Technical Data** , including internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.
  * **Profile Data** , including your username and password, along with other data you may input (eg. portfolio information).
  * **Usage Data** , including information about how you use our website, products and services.
  * **Communications Data** , including your preferences in receiving editorial content and marketing from us and our third parties.

We may also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data**. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal information but is not considered personal information in law as this data does **not** directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature.

We do not collect any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you. Special Categories means sensitive personal data for example but not limited to racial origin, or data concerning health.

## Collecting Personal Information

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

  * **Direct interactions.** You may give us your Identity, Contact and Profile Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us. This includes personal data you provide when you create an account on our website, subscribe to our service or sign up to receive communications from us.
  * **Automated technologies or interactions.** As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies and other similar technologies.
  * **Third parties or publicly available sources.** We may receive Technical Data about you from analytics providers, advertising networks and search information providers. We may also receive Contact and Transaction Data from providers of technical or payment services.

## Using your Personal Information

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

**Where it is necessary for the performance of a contract with you**

For example, we need to process your Identity Data and Profile Data in order to provide you with access to your account. We also need to process your Contact Data and Transaction Data in order to collect and keep record of your payment for your subscription.

**Where it is necessary for regulatory compliance with a legal or regulatory regulation**

For example, we need to process your Transaction Data in order to meet our financial reporting obligations. We may also be required to process personal data in order assist regulatory investigations into market abuse.

**Where we have your consent**

Where we do not have an existing relationship with you (ie. where you do not have an active account with us), we will ask for your consent before sending you any marketing communications. We will always get your consent before we share your personal data with any company outside of Stockopedia for marketing purposes. You can ask us or consented third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by logging into your account and managing your communication preferences, or by following the opt-out links on communications sent to you. You may also contact us at any time.

**Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests**

In some instances, we process your information for our legitimate interests. For example:

  * We process your Technical and Usage Data for the purposes of providing, maintaining, and improving the website.
  * If you have an active account with us, we will use your Identity, Contact, Communications and Usage Data to send you editorial content, product and marketing communications to inform you about our services. You can manage your communication preferences at any time by visiting your account, or by following the opt-out links on communications sent to you.
  * We use Technical, Usage and Profile Data to develop new products and features that are useful for our users, to understand how people use our services, to ensure and improve the performance of our website, and to customise our services to provide you with a better user experience.
  * We use Identity, Transaction, Technical, Profile and Usage Data to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, abuse, security, or technical issues with our website.
  * We use personal data to help us target audiences via third party advertisers. You can opt out of this processing at any time by contacting us at support @ stockopedia.com.

You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us.

## Using Cookies

We use cookies on our website. A cookie consists of information sent by a web server to a web browser, and stored by the browser. The information is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. This enables the web server to identify and track the web browser.

We may use both "session" cookies and "persistent" cookies on the website. The session cookies enable our website to keep track of you whilst you navigate the website. The persistent cookies will enable our website to recognise your computer when you visit our website.

Whilst session cookies will be deleted from your computer when you close your browser, persistent cookies will remain stored on your computer until deleted, or until they reach a specified expiry date.

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies. (For example, in Internet Explorer you can refuse all cookies by clicking "Tools", "Internet Options", "Privacy", and selecting "Block all cookies" using the sliding selector.) This will, however, have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites, including ours.

We use remarketing to advertise across websites, via cookies. Google, Facebook (and other similar third parties, if you use them) will show ads across websites that you are visiting. These ads shown across other websites are based on a user's past visits to our web site by using cookies. Should you wish to opt out of remarketing campaigns, you can do this by visiting Google and Facebook's Ads Settings page.

In addition, we use Google Analytics to analyse the use of this website. Google Analytics generates statistical and other information about website use by means of cookies. The information generated relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of the website.

## Sharing your Personal Information

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out above.

**Internal Third Parties**

We share your personal data with other companies in the Stockopedia Group who provide IT, data, support and system administration services.

**External Third Parties**

We share your personal data with carefully selected service providers who help us with the day-to-day running of our business (such as payment providers), as well as external third party processors who provide us with software tools to manage our customer support, marketing campaigns and business analytics.

We may also share your personal data with third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We only permit our third-party service providers to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

## International Transfers

We share your personal data within the Stockopedia Group, which will involve transferring your data outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ). Many of our external third parties are also based outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ) so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

  * We will transfer personal data to a country recognised by the European Commission as providing an adequate level of data protection (adequacy decision).
  * We may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe.
  * Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US.

## Securing your Personal Information

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees or contracted third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

All personal information you provide will be stored on our secure servers. Please note that if you contribute publicly to the community (such as commenting on discussion boards) your name will be publicly visible unless you choose to use a pseudonym which can be edited at any time.

If you choose to publish information about yourself in your public profile or in articles you choose to publish on the website (both optional), this information will, of course, be publicly available on the internet.

All personal data and payment information is sent over a secure protocol, but please note that data transmission over the internet is inherently insecure and cannot be guaranteed.

All passwords are stored in our database using one way encryption and cannot be read by employees. You are responsible for keeping your password and user details confidential. We will only ask you for your password when you log in.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

## Retaining your Personal Information

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

If reasonably necessary or required to meet legal or regulatory requirements, resolve disputes, prevent fraud and abuse, or enforce our Terms of Use, we may keep hold of some of your information as required, even after you have closed your account. For example, by law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity and Transaction Data) for six years after they cease being customers for tax purposes.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Your Legal Rights below for further information.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for record-keeping, research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

## Your Legal Rights

If you are habitually located in the European Union, you have the right to access, rectify, download or erase your information, as well as the right to restrict and object to certain processing of your information. While some of these rights apply generally, certain rights apply only in certain limited circumstances. We describe these rights below:

  * **Access:** You can access much of your information by logging into your account. If you require additional access or if you are not a Stockopedia member, contact us at support @ stockopedia.com. To download a copy of your data, visit your account.
  * **Porting:** We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. You can download a copy of your data from your account.
  * **Rectify, Restrict, Limit, Delete:** You can also rectify, restrict, limit or delete much of your information by logging into your account. If you are unable to do this, please contact us at support @ stockopedia.com. 
  * **Object:** Where we process your information based on our legitimate interests explained above, you can object to this processing in certain circumstances, by contacting us at support @ stockopedia.com. In such cases, we will cease processing your information unless we have compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing or where it is needed for legal reasons.
  * **Revoke consent:** Where you have previously provided your consent, such as to receive certain communications, you have the right to withdraw your consent to the processing of your information at any time. For example, you can withdraw your consent by updating your communication settings. In certain cases, we may continue to process your information after you have withdrawn consent if we have a legal basis to do so or if your withdrawal of consent was limited to certain processing activities.
  * **Complain:** You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues. We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance. You can find further information about the ICO at <https://ico.org.uk/>. 

#### What we need from you

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data or to exercise any of the other rights. However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data or to exercise any of your other rights. This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

## Changes to the Privacy Policy and your duty to inform us of changes

Where we make changes to our privacy notice we shall let you know. It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

This version was last updated on 21 May 2018.
